<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meet Chandershekhar</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Meet Chandershekhar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Junior Year Is Over Already????</title>
      <link>/blog/junior-year-is-over-already/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/junior-year-is-over-already/</guid>
      <description>My Thoughts Well, I have to say this year is one to remember. Who ever thought COVID-19 would turn our lives upside down in a matter of weeks. It is still feels unreal to say that I was walking outside and hanging out with my friends, but now I am cooped up inside my house living with trepidation of not knowing what will happen next. The most difficult part to fathom is that I will not be able to see my friends for almost 6 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Isolation</title>
      <link>/poetry/social-isolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/poetry/social-isolation/</guid>
      <description>  People wait for their chance  To go out and have a dance  Yet he still prowls in wait  Waiting of your date  Nothing is more morbid  Than COVID of the horrid  He journeys to the lungs  And there remains clung  May all proceed with caution  Or fight him as an option   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDS 348 Project 2</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>Chandershekhar Shori, EID–cs56788
Introduction: The dataset chosen for this project is the SLID dataset, which can be found in the carData package and accessed by using library(carData). Each row of this dataset represents information collected from a single individual living in the Canadian province of Ontario and is part of the workforce. For this purposes of this project only complete data provided by individuals will be used for this project, and any rows containing NA values will be removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I use R, Python, or both?</title>
      <link>/blog/should-i-use-r-python-or-both/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/should-i-use-r-python-or-both/</guid>
      <description>Python Python and R are both fascinating on their own. However when put together, these two softwares can become a powerful tool that can solve complex issues. Below we have an example of how we have used Python to determine all possible k-mers of a particular sequence, which is particularly very useful in the field of bioinformatics.
##Python Chunk my_seq = &amp;quot;ATCATCATG&amp;quot; def k_mercount(sequence): subs = [sequence[x:x+3] for x in range(len(sequence)) if len(sequence[x:x+3]) &amp;gt; 2] kmers = {} for i in subs: if i in kmers: kmers[i] += 1 else: kmers[i] = 1 print(kmers) k_mercount(my_seq) ## {&amp;#39;ATG&amp;#39;: 1, &amp;#39;CAT&amp;#39;: 2, &amp;#39;ATC&amp;#39;: 2, &amp;#39;TCA&amp;#39;: 2}  R Now we will demonstrate the use of R on a dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDS 348 Project 1</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>Chandershekhar Shori, EID–cs56788
Introduction: The first data set chosen for this project is the lung dataset. The lung dataset contains data about survival among patients from the North Central Cancer Treatment Group. This dataset contains 10 variables, and these variables are inst, time, status, age, sex, ph.ecog, ph.karno, pat.karno, meal.cal, and wt.loss. The inst variable represents the institution code, the time variable represents the survival time in days, the status variable represents the censoring status, the age variable represents the age in years, meal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>